Finding Aid for Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (University of Michigan) records, 1961-[ongoing]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Grants 1965-2000, 13 linear feet
  - Instructional Development Fund
    - 1973-1980
      - Warner, Kenneth; Public Health 1978-1979 (Box 11)
      - Wasserman, Arthur; Mathematics 1977-1978 (Box 11)
      - Weintraub, Daniel; Psychology 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Whitting, Allen; Political Science
        - 1973-1974 (Box 11)
        - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Willis, E.; Speech Communication 1973-1974 (Box 11)
      - Women's Studies 1973-1974 (Box 11)
      - Wolf, Louis; Mechanical Engineering 1975-1976 (Box 11)
      - Zald, May er; Education 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Zorach, Cecille; Residential College-German 1978-1979 (Box 11)
      - Zorn, Frances; Residential College 1975-1976 (Box 11)
      - Requests Not Funded 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Proposals Rejected 1977-1978 (Box 11)
      - General 1975-1976 (Box 11)
    - General Information 1974-2000
      - 1974-1989, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - 1990-1995, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - 1996-2000, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous Grants
    - 1965-1973
      - Wolverine Fund, General Material 1965-1971 (Box 11)
      - Astronomy; Instructional Development Fund 1972 (Box 11)
      - Biological Chemistry; Instructional Development Fund 1971 (Box 11)
      - Biology; Special Projects Fund (Box 12)
      - Computer Assisted Education 1965-1970 (Box 12)
      - Chemistry Department 1971 (Box 12)
      - Coalition for Use of Learning School 1971-1973 (Box 12)
      - Dentistry; Instructional Development Fund 1972 (Box 12)
      - Economics; Daniel Fusfeld; Instructional Development Fund 1969-1971 (Box 12)
      - Electrical Engineering; Ward Getty; Wolverine Fund 1970 (Box 12)
      - Engineering; Instructional Development Fund 1972 (Box 12)
      - English; Jensen; Special Projects Account 1969-1970 (Box 12)
      - History; John Bowditch 1971 (Box 12)
      - History; R.G. Schafer 1968-1969 (Box 12)
      - History; Ray Waggoner 1970 (Box 12)
      - Institute for Social Research; Special Projects Fund 1973 (Box 12)
      - Journalism; John Bishop; Special Projects Fund 1966-1972, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - Journalism; John Field; Special Projects Fund 1972-1973 (Box 12)
      - Library Science; Rose Vainstien; Wolverine Fund 1969 (Box 12)
      - Medical School; Andrew Zweifler; Wolverine Fund 1970 (Box 12)
      - Mental Health Research Institute; Wolverine Fund 1969 (Box 12)
      - Natural Resources; James Swan; Instructional Development Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Physics; Noah Sherman; Special Projects Account 1970 (Box 12)
      - Pilot Program; Tom Lobe; Instructional Development Fund 1972 (Box 12)
      - Political Science; James Eisenstein; Instructional Development Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Political Science; Joel Samoff; Instructional Development Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Program for Educational and Social Change; Instructional Development Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Psychology; Sue Golden; Special Projects Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Psychology; Sabin Head; Wolverine Fund 1970 (Box 12)
      - Psychology; Dana Main; Instructional Development Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Psychology; Richard Mann; Special Projects Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Psychology; Ranier Von Konigslow 1971 (Box 12)
      - Residential College; Special Projects Fund 1967-1971 (Box 12)
      - Romance Languages; Marcel Muller; Instructional Development Fund 1971 (Box 12)
      - Television Center; Special Projects Fund 1966-1973 (Box 12)
    - CRLT Faculty Associates Program
      - General, 1995-96 (Box 21)
      - Faculty Associates, 1995-96
        - Brown, M., LS&A-Math (Box 21)
        - Chesler, M., LS&A (Box 21)
        - Coppola, B., LS&A (Box 21)
        - Montogomery, S., Engineering (Box 21)
      - General, 1996-99, 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Interdisciplinary Faculty Associates Program Grant (IFA)
      - General, Winter 1999 (Box 21)
      - Winter 1999 Unfunded
        - Batra, et. al., Business (Box 21)
        - Cogswell and Tillinghast, LS&A and Art & Design (Box 21)
        - Duanmu, et. al., LS&A-Linguistics (Box 21)
        - Fahenstiel, et. al., School of Natural Resources (SNRE) (Box 21)
        - Lopez-Cotin and Granzow-de la Corda, LS&A-Residential College (Box 21)
        - McClamroch and Fishstrom, Engineering (Box 21)
        - Rabkin and Simon, LS&A-English (Box 21)
        - Rayher and May lie, LS&A-Film and Video Studies (Box 21)
        - Rodemer and Rush, Art & Design (Box 21)
        - Sarris and Fogel, LS&A (Box 21)
        - Standifer, et. al., Music (Box 21)
      - Winter 1999 Funded
        - Algase, et. al., Nursing (Box 21)
        - Amrine and Eley, LS&A-German (Box 21)
        - Badgley and Smuts, LS&A-Residential College (Box 21)
        - Simons and Traub, LS&A-History of Art and English (Box 21)
        - Yervasi and Young, LS&A-Romance Languages and Architecture & Urban Planning (Box 21)
      - General, Fall 1999 (Box 21)
      - Fall 1999 Unfunded
        - Leonard and Hass, LS&A-Women's Studies and Art & Design (Box 21)
        - Nori and Winful, LS&A-Physics and Engineering (Box 21)
        - Suarez and Velez-Aguayo, LS&A-Romance Languages and Music (Box 21)
      - Fall 1999 Funded
        - Cogswell and Tillinghast, LS&A-English and Art & Design (Box 21)
        - Maio and Blow, Medical School (Box 21)
        - Shier and Myers, LS&A-Residential College and Psychology (Box 21)
        - Turan and Collins, Engineering and Architecture & Urban Design (Box 21)
    - Lecturers' Professional Development Fund Grant (LPDF)
      - General 1996-1999, 3 folders (Box 21)
      - Winter 1999 Funded
        - Balducci, C., LS&A-Residential College (Box 21)
        - Colling, K., Nursing (Box 21)
        - Goodenough, E., LS&A-Residential College (Box 21)
        - Heirich, J., LS&A-Residential College (Box 21)
        - Howlin, R., Social Work (Box 21)
        - Iwamoto, L., Architecture & Urban Planning (Box 21)
        - Nysenholc, J., LS&A-Judaic Studies (Box 21)
        - Sarris, T., LS&A-Film and Video Studies (Box 21)
        - Schooler, E., Art & Design (Box 21)
        - Van Riper, S., Nursing (Box 21)
        - Walton, S., LS&A-Residential College (Box 21)
        - Weller, A., LS&A-Asia Language and Culture (Box 21)
    - Multicultural Learning and Teaching Initiatives Fund (MuLTI Fund)
      - General, 1995-98, 3 folders (Box 21)
      - 1997-98, Unfunded
        - Soo/Marzolf, Architecture and Urban Planning (Box 21)
      - 1997-98, Funded
        - Burton, D., Social Work (Box 21)
        - Gant, L., Social Work (Box 21)
        - Gutierrez, L., LS&A (Box 21)
        - Sheets, et. al., Medical School (Box 21)
    - Whitaker Fund for the Improvement of Teaching
      - General, Fall 1999 (Round I) (Box 21)
      - Fall 1999 Unfunded
        - Amrine, F., LS&A-German (Box 21)
        - Burkel, W., Medical School (Box 21)
        - Cortwright, G., Medical School (Box 21)
        - Edwards, P., LS&A-Residential College (Box 21)
        - Gest, T., Medical School (Box 21)
        - Gest T., Medical School (Box 21)
        - Glover, R., Medical School (Box 21)
        - Harrison, K., Kinesiology (Box 21)
        - Kim, S-K., Medical School (Box 21)
        - Ledwon, D., Nursing (Box 21)
        - Marshall, K., Medical School (Box 21)
        - Nornes, A., LS&A-Film and Video Studies (Box 21)
        - Nori, F., LS&A (Box 21)
        - Pijanowski, H., Art & Design (Box 21)
        - Sirviente, A., Engineering (Box 21)
        - Turan, M., Architecture & Urban Planning (Box 21)
        - Wineman and Tryggvson, Engineering (Box 21)
      - Fall 1999 Funded
        - Bright, C., LS&A (Box 22)
        - Freudenberg, J., Engineering (Box 22)
        - Gonzalez, R., LS&A Romance Language and Literature (Box 22)
        - Hagerty, B., Nursing (Box 22)
        - Hassinger and Groat, LS&A and Architecture & Urban Planning (Box 22)
        - McEnnerney, D., LS&A (Box 22)
        - Van der Pluijm, B., LS&A-Geological Science (Box 22)
        - Wang, H., Engineering (Box 22)
      - General, Winter 1999 (Round II) (Box 22)
      - Winter 1999 Unfunded
        - Furney and Stern, Medical School (Box 22)
        - Jamin, S., Engineering (Box 22)
        - Loch-Caruso, R., Public Health (Box 22)
        - Pohl, J., Nursing (Box 22)
      - Winter 1999 Funded
        - Gant, L., Social Work (Box 22)
        - McKay/Yalisove, Engineering (Box 22)
        - Yoshihana, M., Social Work (Box 22)
      - General 1997 (Round I) (Box 22)
      - Fall 1997 Funded
        - Gant, L., Social Work (Box 22)
        - Gernes, T., LS&A-English (Box 22)
        - Gikandi, S., LS&A-Comparative Literature (Box 22)
        - Jamin, S., Engineering (Box 22)
        - Loch-Caruso, R., Public Health (Box 22)
        - McKay, T., LS&A-Physics (Box 22)
        - Pohl, J., Nursing (Box 22)
        - Stern and Furney, LS&A (Box 22)
        - Yalisove, S., Engineering (Box 22)
        - Yoshihama, M., Social Work (Box 22)
      - Winter 1997 Unfunded
        - Gere, A., LS&A-English and Education (Box 22)
        - Gocek, F., LS&A-Sociology (Box 22)
        - Low and Grese, School of Natural Resources (SNRE) (Box 22)
        - Simoni, M., Music (Box 22)
      - Winter 1997 Funded
        - Rodemer/Staples, Art & Design (Box 22)
        - Simons, P., LS&A-History of Art (Box 22)
        - Steneck, N., Engineering (Box 22)
      - General, Fall 1996(Round I) (Box 22)
      - Fall 1996 Funded
        - Gere, A., LS&A-English and Education (Box 22)
        - Gocek, F., LS&A-Sociology (Box 22)
        - Hinman, P., LS&A-Math (Box 22)
        - Low, B., School of Natural Resources (SNRE) (Box 22)
        - Osgood and Ocorr, LS&A (Box 22)
        - Rodemer and Staples, Art & Design (Box 22)
        - Simoni, M., Music (Box 22)
        - Simons, P., LS&A-History of Art (Box 22)
        - Smith, S., LS&A-Women's Studies (Box 22)
        - Steneck, N., Engineering (Box 22)
      - General, Winter 1996 (Round II) (Box 22)
      - Winter 1996 Unfunded
        - Grew, R., LS&A-History (Box 22)
        - Groat and Sutton, Architecture & Urban Planning (Box 22)
        - Inglehart, M., Dentistry (Box 22)
        - Jones/Montgomery, Engineering (Box 22)
        - Sanchez, G., LS&A-American Culture (Box 22)
      - Winter 1996 Funded
        - Dressler, M., LS&A-German (Box 22)
        - Gurin, P., LS&A-Psychology (Box 22)
        - Vicinus, M., LS&A-English (Box 22)
      - General 1995 (Round I) (Box 22)
      - Fall 1995 Funded
        - Dressler, M., LS&A-German (Box 22)
        - Grew, R., LS&A-History (Box 22)
        - Groat and Sutton, Architecture & Urban Planning (Box 22)
        - Gurin, P., LS&A-Psychology (Box 22)
        - Hymans and Gordon, LS&A-Economics (Box 22)
        - Inglehart, M., Dentistry (Box 22)
        - Jones and Montgomery, Engineering (Box 22)
        - Sanchez, G., LS&A-American Culture (Box 22)
        - Sulzby, S., Education (Box 22)
        - Vicinus, M., LS&A-English (Box 22)
- Workshops and Seminars 1960-2004, 2 linear feet
  The Workshops and Seminars series (2.0 linear feet) covers 1960-2004, although most material is from the period 1981-2004. Documentation includes publicity, outlines, and course material for CRLT sponsored instructional workshops and seminars.
  - Brochures
    - Faculty Programs and Grants Calendars 1994-2004 (Box 22)
    - General 1963-2000 (Box 22)
    - Graduate Student Instructor (GSI) Workshop Calendars 1982-2003 (Box 22)
    - Instructional Workshops and Colloquia Calendars 1979-1994 (Box 23)
  - CRLT Instructional Workshops, Administrative Materials
    - Correspondence about Potential Workshop on Small Group Instructional Diagnosis 1981 (Box 23)
    - Instructional Workshop Participation Counts 1981-1983 (Box 23)
    - Instructional Workshop Reports 1981 (Box 23)
    - Effective Lecture Management February 19, 1981 (Box 23)
    - Teaching Critical Thinking October 5, 1983 (Box 23)
    - Teaching Professional Skills October 15, 1983 (Box 23)
    - Classroom Lecturer and Discussion Management November 14, 1983 (Box 23)
    - Grading March 7, 1984 (Box 23)
    - Feedback Lecture January 22, 1987 (Box 23)
    - Stimulating Critical Thinking January 29, 1987 (Box 23)
    - Strengthening Students' Writing Skills October 13, 1988 (Box 23)
    - Time Management November 1988 (Box 23)
    - Designing and Evaluating Tests October 11, 1989 (Box 23)
    - 35mm Slide Production October 24, 1989 (Box 23)
    - Introduction to Preparing Graphics for Instructional or Professional Presentations October 30, 1989 (Box 23)
    - Understanding Performance Anxiety November 8, 1989 (Box 23)
    - Using A-V Materials in Presentations September 26, 1990 (Box 23)
  - CRLT Sponsored Workshops and Seminars Materials
    - Beginnings: Creating Climates for Learning October 8, 1990 (Box 23)
    - Preparing Graphics for Instructional and Professional Presentations, October 18, 25, and November 1, 1990 (Box 23)
    - Critical Thinking October 24, 1990 (Box 23)
    - Building Better Tests, Fall 1990 (Box 23)
    - Getting Students to Think February 12, 1990 (Box 23)
    - 35mm Slide Production March 15, 1990 (Box 23)
    - Using Small-Group Activities to Enhance Learning January 30, 1991 (Box 23)
    - Speaking Skills, February 4, 11, and 16 1991 (Box 23)
    - Advanced Graphics 1991 (Box 23)
    - Lecturing, Winter 1991 (Box 23)
    - Presentation Planning, Winter 1991 (Box 23)
    - Writing in the Science Classes, Winter 1991 (Box 23)
    - Multicultural Teaching September 3, 1991 (Box 23)
    - Guide for Analyzing Explanations January 6, 1992 (Box 23)
    - Giving Explanations February 5, 1992 (Box 23)
    - Effective Lecturing II, Fall 1992 (Box 23)
    - Effective Lecturing January 1993 (Box 23)
    - Discussion: Method Teaching, no date but prior to 1994 (Box 23)
    - Getting Students to Think, no date but prior to 1994 (Box 23)
    - Agenda for Questioning, no date but prior to 1994 (Box 23)
    - Building a Teaching Portfolio 1994 (Box 23)
    - Cooperative Learning and Lecturing (Active Learning) 1994 (Box 23)
    - Authority and Identity: Balancing Content and Student Participation February 27, 1996 (Box 23)
    - The Teaching Portfolio February 24, 1998 (Box 23)
    - An Introduction to Electronic Presentation Technology in the Classroom March 11, 1998 (Box 23)
    - Developing Course Web Pages: An Introduction September 16, 1998 (Box 23)
    - Incorporating Interactivity Into Your Web Site September 23, 1998 (Box 23)
    - Crossing the Great Divide: A Dialogue with Students About What Really Happens in the Classroom October 1, 1998 (Box 23)
    - Creating Course Web Pages October 6, 1998 (Box 23)
    - Leading Controversial Discussions October 7, 1998 (Box 23)
    - How Many People Did the Reading November 2, 1998 (Box 23)
    - Developing Course Web Pages: An Introduction January 21, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Planning Your Own Course January 26, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Fostering Critical Thinking January 27, 1999 (Box 23)
    - The Teaching Portfolio: Getting Started February 9, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Speaking Skills in Classroom Settings February 10, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Managing Your Class February 22, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Student Learning Outside the Classroom March 11, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Practical Strategies for Engaging Students in Learning March 15, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Working with New GSIs: Strategies and Approaches August 23, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Tools and Strategies for Effective Online Discussions October 10, 2000 (Box 23)
    - Faculty Using Technology to Enhance Learning: Tools, Techniques, and Success Stories October 19, 2000 (Box 23)
    - Multicultural Course Transformation October 24, 2000 (Box 23)
    - Teaching Portfolio February 2001 (Box 23)
    - Speaking Skills in Classroom Settings, February 6 and 13 2001 (Box 23)
    - Leading Discussions on Controversial Topics February 7, 2001 (Box 23)
    - Speaking Skills in Classroom Settings, February 8 and 15 2001 (Box 23)
    - Getting Students Actively Involved in Large Lecture Classes February 14, 2001 (Box 23)
    - Collaborative Learning in Small Groups and Semester Projects February 19, 2001 (Box 23)
    - Faculty Using Technology to Enhance Learning: Tools, Techniques, and Success (Box 23)
    - Evaluating Student Writing August 28, 2001 (Box 23)
    - Teaching for Critical Thinking and Self-Authorship September 20, 2001 (Box 23)
    - The Multicultural Classroom and Social Justice: Strategies for Inclusion and Effectiveness October 3, 2001 (Box 23)
    - Using Technology to Promote Active Learning October 4, 2001 (Box 24)
    - Collaborative Learning in Small Groups and Semester Projects October 25, 2001 (Box 24)
    - Preparing Future Faculty Luncheon: The Role of Technology in Higher Education 2001 (Box 24)
    - Fundamentals of Lecturing January 30, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Preparing Future Faculty for Social Science GSIs: Reconciling our Values and Our Disciplines February 1, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Evaluating Student Writing February 4, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Preparing Future Faculty Luncheon for Science, Math, and Engineering GSIs: Controversy and Argument for Further Learning February 9, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Placing Your Course in the World: Global Implications and Undergraduate Teaching February 14, 2002 (Box 24)
    - When Race Breaks Out February 18, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Using Power Point to Enhance Classroom Lecturers and Demonstrations February 19, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Academic Integrity in the Classroom March 18, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Learning in the Sciences: Moving Active Learning from the Lab to the Lecture March 19, 2002 (Box 24)
    - Speaking Skills: Improving Instructional Presentations, Winter 2002 (Box 24)
    - The Engaged Classroom: Getting Students Involved in the Learning Process September 30, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Effective Classroom Communication Skills, October 1 and 8 2003 (Box 24)
    - Using UM CourseTools in Large Lecture Courses October 15, 2003 (Box 24)
    - CRLT Players' First Days Sketch October 22, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Teaching for Inclusion October 27, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Advice on Writing Better Tests October 31, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Gathering Feedback on Student Learning November 3, 2003 (Box 24)
    - CRLT Players' Advance Faculty Meeting Sketch November 5, 2003 (Box 24)
    - CRLT Players' Voices and Visions of Diversity Sketch November 13, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Getting Ready for an Academic Career November 17, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Brown vs. Board of Education Theme Semester Roundtable January 21, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Evaluating Student Writing January 28, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Using Instructional Technology to Engage Students February 2, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Successfully Implementing Team Work in the Sciences and Mathematics February 3, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Fostering Critical Thinking February 9, 2004 (Box 24)
    - What Research Tells Us About Effective College Teaching February 12, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Effective Student Presentations February 17, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Measuring ABET Objectives in the Engineering Classroom February 18, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Negotiating Instructor Identity in the Classroom March 3, 2004 (Box 24)
    - Elements of a Teaching Portfolio March 3, 2004 (Box 24)